Simon, Fanny Records on Microfilm 5169 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Fanny Simon Records on Microfilm
1923-1958
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Simon, S. Fanny, 1903-1989
5169 mf
0.89 cubic feet
8 microfilm reels
Records, microfilm.
Microfilm copy of the Latin American Booklet Pamphlet Collection
16213830
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, September 27, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, November 01, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Fanny Simon was born in 1903 and came to the U.S. from Warsaw just before the outbreak of World War I. A lifelong socialist - she was attracted to the socialists and Eugene Debs for their steadfast opposition to the "capitalists' war" - she joined the Socialist Party in 1929.
She was a brillian student and won a scholarship to Cornell and later went on to Columbia where she received a doctorate in economics. In 1940 she co-authored a book titled 'The American Labor Movement'.
Fanny Simon was a fixture around the United Federation of Teachers well into her 80s, she was one of the founding mothers of Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) and the UFT's Women's Rights Committee, and even found time to work with the labor movement in Mexico.
Scope and Contents
There is a negative copy available upon request.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5169: Fanny Simon Records
Simon, S. Fanny, 1903-1989
16213830
- Latin American Booklet Pamphlet Collection (positive) (Reel 1)
  - Box: 1, Folder: 1, 1 (Reel 1)
    - Item 1: Lax F.O.R.A., 1933; 1; Publication (Reel 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Author: Abad de Santillan, Diego
      Format: Publication
      Language: English.
  - Box: 1, Folder: 2, 2; Publication (Reel 1)
    - Item 1: Necesidades y Posibilidades Agrarias de Mexico, 1938; 2; Publication (Reel 1)
      Author: Aguirre, Norberto
  - Box: 1, Folder: 3, 3; Publication (Reel 1)
    - Item 1: Una Etapa Politica del Socialismo Ecuatoriana, 1946; 3; Publication (Reel 1)
      Author: Agustin Aguirre, Manuel
  - Box: 1, Folder: 4, 4; Publication (Reel 1)
    - Item 1: Vida Ejemolar de Jose Ingenieros, 1936; 4; Publication (Reel 1)
      Author: Bagu, Sergio
  - Box: 1, Folder: 5, 5; Publication (Reel 1)
    - Item 1: Politique Commerciale du Bresil, 5; Publication (Reel 1)
      Author: Bandeira de Mello, Affonso de Toledo
- Latin American Booklet Pamphlet Collection (positive), Publication (Reel 2)
  - Box: 2, Folder: 1, 1; Publication (Reel 2)
    - Item 1: Instituto Brasileiro de Geografia e Estatistica (Brazilian Institute of Geography and Statistics), 1939; 1; Publication (Reel 2)
  - Box: 2, Folder: 2, 2; Publication (Reel 2)
    - Item 1: Potos I Colonial, 1939; 2; Publication (Reel 2)
      Author: Canete y Dominquez, Don Pedro Vicente
  - Box: 2, Folder: 3, 3; Publication (Reel 2)
    - Item 1: Suelda y Salariose Minimos Vitales, 1947; 3; Publication (Reel 2)
      Author: de las Casa, Luis F.
  - Box: 2, Folder: 4, 4; Publication (Reel 2)
    - Item 1: I Partidos de Frente Unico Para Indoamerica!, 1938; 4; Publication (Reel 2)
  - Box: 2, Folder: 5, 5; Publication (Reel 2)
    - Item 1: Solidardad con el Pueblo Paraguayo, 1943; 5; Publication (Reel 2)
  - Box: 2, Folder: 6, 6; Publication (Reel 2)
    - Item 1: Memoria C.R.O.M., 1926; 6; Publication (Reel 2)
  - Box: 2, Folder: 7, 7; Publication (Reel 2)
    - Item 1: Memoria C.R.O.M. 1935, 7; Publication (Reel 2)
- Latin American Booklet Pamphlet Collection (positive), Publication (Reel 3)
  - Box: 3, Folder: 1, 1; Publication (Reel 3)
    - Item 1: Democracia Cuantitiva y Democracia Cualitativa, 1920; 1; Publication (Reel 3)
      Author: Dickmann, Enrique
  - Box: 3, Folder: 2, 2; Publication (Reel 3)
    - Item 1: Visiones de Chile, 1936; 2; Publication (Reel 3)
  - Box: 3, Folder: 3, 3; Publication (Reel 3)
    - Item 1: Boletin. II (December, 1939), 3; Publication (Reel 3)
  - Box: 3, Folder: 4, 4; Publication (Reel 3)
    - Item 1: Malatesta, 1945; 4; Publication (Reel 3)
      Author: Fabbri, Luis
      Notes: Translated from Italian into Spanish by Diego A. De Santillan
  - Box: 3, Folder: 5, 5; Publication (Reel 3)
    - Item 1: Almanaque de la Cooperacion, Ano 1940, 5; Publication (Reel 3)
  - Box: 3, Folder: 6, 6; Publication (Reel 3)
    - Item 1: Cursos, 1938, Escuela de la Cooperacion, 6; Publication (Reel 3)
  - Box: 3, Folder: 7, 7; Publication (Reel 3)
    - Item 1: Historia de los Sistemas Economicas, 1935; 7; Publication (Reel 3)
      Author: Ferrara, Romeo
  - Box: 3, Folder: 8, 8; Publication (Reel 3)
    - Item 1: Revolution versus Imperialismo (en la Comarca Lagunera), 1936; 8; Publication (Reel 3)
      Author: Flores Munos, Gilberto
  - Box: 3, Folder: 9, 9; Publication (Reel 3)
    - Item 1: Los Tres Mensajes, 1947; 9; Publication (Reel 3)
      Author: Franco, Pedro B.
  - Box: 3, Folder: 10, 10; Publication (Reel 3)
    - Item 1: Ensayos Sobre Marxismo, 1936; 10; Publication (Reel 3)
      Author: Frugoni, Emilio
  - Box: 3, Folder: 11, 11; Publication (Reel 3)
    - Item 1: Genesis, Esencia y Fundamentos del Socialismo Tomo II, 1947; 11; Publication (Reel 3)
- Latin American Booklet Pamphlet Collection (positive), Publication (Reel 4)
  - Box: 4, Folder: 1, 1; Publication (Reel 4)
    - Item 1: Discurso, 1947; 1; Publication (Reel 4)
      Author: Gallegos, Romulo
  - Box: 4, Folder: 2, 2; Publication (Reel 4)
    - Item 1: 3 Historicos Documentos, 1941; 2; Publication (Reel 4)
  - Box: 4, Folder: 3, 3; Publication (Reel 4)
    - Item 1: La Situacion de la Industria Minera, 1929; 3; Publication (Reel 4)
      Author: Garcia, G.P.
  - Box: 4, Folder: 4, 4; Publication (Reel 4)
    - Item 1: America, XIV (no.68), 1939; 4; Publication (Reel 4)
  - Box: 4, Folder: 5, 5; Publication (Reel 4)
    - Item 1: El Antimperialismo y El Apra, 1936; 5; Publication (Reel 4)
      Author: Hayla de la Torre, V.R.
  - Box: 4, Folder: 6, 6; Publication (Reel 4)
    - Item 1: A Donde Va Indoamerica?, 1936; 6; Publication (Reel 4)
      Author: Haya de la Torre, Victor Raul
  - Box: 4, Folder: 7, 7; Publication (Reel 4)
    - Item 1: Boletin de Informaciones y de Estudios Sociales y Economicos 11 (April, 1940), 7; Publication (Reel 4)
  - Box: 4, Folder: 8, 8; Publication (Reel 4)
    - Item 1: As Duas Batalhas de Guararapes, 1939; 8; Publication (Reel 4)
      Author: Lobato Filho, General
  - Box: 4, Folder: 9, 9; Publication (Reel 4)
    - Item 1: El Socialisma en Yucatan, 1923; 9; Publication (Reel 4)
      Author: Loveira,Carlos
      Language: Spanish.
  - Box: 4, Folder: 10, 10; Publication (Reel 4)
    - Item 1: Quettara Mi Pais en Sers Anos, 1935; 10; Publication (Reel 4)
      Author: Luna Arroyo, Antonio
  - Box: 4, Folder: 11, 11; Publication (Reel 4)
    - Item 1: El Sindicalismo y El Cooperativismo, 1943; 11; Publication (Reel 4)
      Author: Maldonado Jarrin, Gonzalo
  - Box: 4, Folder: 12, 12; Publication (Reel 4)
    - Item 1: Directorio de Asociaciones Sindicales de la Republica Mexicana, 1934; 12; Publication (Reel 4)
  - Box: 4, Folder: 13, 13; Publication (Reel 4)
    - Item 1: Directorio de Asociaciones Sindicales de la Republica, 1935; 13; Publication (Reel 4)
- Latin American Booklet Pamphlet Collection (positive), Publication (Reel 5)
  - Box: 5, Folder: 1, 1; Publication (Reel 5)
    - Item 1: Industria, Comercio y Trabajo, 1928; 1; Publication (Reel 5)
      Author: Morones, Luis N.
  - Box: 5, Folder: 2, 2; Publication (Reel 5)
    - Item 1: El Pueblo Continente, 1939; 2; Publication (Reel 5)
      Author: Orrego, Antenor
  - Box: 5, Folder: 3, 3; Publication (Reel 5)
    - Item 1: Declaracion de Principios, 1938; 3; Publication (Reel 5)
  - Box: 5, Folder: 4, 4; Publication (Reel 5)
    - Item 1: Anuario Socialista. 1947, 4; Publication (Reel 5)
  - Box: 5, Folder: 5, 5; Publication (Reel 5)
    - Item 1: Batlle y El Proceso Historico del Uruguay, 5; Publication (Reel 5)
      Author: Pintos, Francisco R.
  - Box: 5, Folder: 6, 6; Publication (Reel 5)
    - Item 1: Haya de la Torre, El Indoamericano, 1946; 6; Publication (Reel 5)
      Author: del Pomar, F. Cossio
- Latin American Booklet Pamphlet Collection (positive), Publication (Reel 6)
  - Box: 6, Folder: 1, 1; Publication (Reel 6)
    - Item 1: La Mujer en El Partido del Pueblo, 1946; 1; Publication (Reel 6)
      Author: Portal, Magda
  - Box: 6, Folder: 2, 2; Publication (Reel 6)
    - Item 1: Propoganda y Ataque, 1939; 2; Publication (Reel 6)
      Author: Prada, Manuel G.
  - Box: 6, Folder: 3, 3; Publication (Reel 6)
    - Item 1: La Protesta XILX (Marzo 15 de 1947), 3; Publication (Reel 6)
  - Box: 6, Folder: 4, 4; Publication (Reel 6)
    - Item 1: Como Nace y se Desarrolla una Cooperativa, 1935; 4; Publication (Reel 6)
      Author: Repetto, Nicolas
  - Box: 6, Folder: 5, 5; Publication (Reel 6)
    - Item 1: Estatistica de Generos de Primeira Necessidade, 1940; 5; Publication (Reel 6)
      Author: Rudolfer, Bruno
      Notes: second author - Oscar Egidio de Araujo
  - Box: 6, Folder: 6, 6; Publication (Reel 6)
    - Item 1: Dialecta y Determinismo, 1938; 6; Publication (Reel 6)
      Author: Sanchez, Luis Alberto
  - Box: 6, Folder: 7, 7; Publication (Reel 6)
    - Item 1: Hombres y Rejas (Men and Prison Bars), 1937; 7; Publication (Reel 6)
      Author: Seoane, Juan
  - Box: 6, Folder: 8, 8; Publication (Reel 6)
    - Item 1: Autopsia del Presupuesto Civilista, 1936; 8; Publication (Reel 6)
      Author: Seoane, Manuel
      Notes: Prologo by V.R. Haya de la Torre
  - Box: 6, Folder: 9, 9; Publication (Reel 6)
    - Item 1: Present Status of the Mexican Oil "Expropriations", 1940; 9; Publication (Reel 6)
  - Box: 6, Folder: 10, 10; Publication (Reel 6)
    - Item 1: Etnografia de Guatemala, 1958; 10; Publication (Reel 6)
      Author: Stoll, Otto
- Latin American Booklet Pamphlet Collection (positive), Publication (Reel 7)
  - Box: 7, Folder: 1, 1; Publication (Reel 7)
    - Item 1: Viente Anos de Lucha!, 1; Publication (Reel 7)
  - Box: 7, Folder: 2, 2; Publication (Reel 7)
    - Item 1: A. Nasao, 1937; 2; Publication (Reel 7)
      Author: Vargas, Getulio
  - Box: 7, Folder: 3, 3; Publication (Reel 7)
    - Item 1: Vidas Minimos, 1933; 3; Publication (Reel 7)
      Author: Vera, Gonzalez
  - Box: 7, Folder: 4, 4; Publication (Reel 7)
    - Item 1: De Frente, March !, 1947; 4; Publication (Reel 7)
      Author: Vera Saglio, Nelly
  - Box: 7, Folder: 5, 5; Publication (Reel 7)
    - Item 1: Bolivia Intima, 1940; 5; Publication (Reel 7)
      Author: Vilela, Arturo
  - Box: 7, Folder: 6, 6; Publication (Reel 7)
    - Item 1: La Lengua de Adan y el Hombre de Tiaguanaco, 1939; 6; Publication (Reel 7)
      Author: Villamil de Rada,k Emeterio
  - Box: 7, Folder: 7, 7; Publication (Reel 7)
    - Item 1: Mexico, D.F., 1938; 7; Publication (Reel 7)
- Latin American Booklet Pamphlet Collection (positive), Publication (Reel 8)
  - Box: 8, Folder: 1, 1; Publication (Reel 8)
    - Item 1: Mexico, 1; Publication (Reel 8)
      Notes: Major sections of this book are missing it appears to be a collection of articles on land reform in the early 1930's in Mexico.
  - Box: 8, Folder: 2, 2; Publication (Reel 8)
    - Item 1: La F.O.R.A. Ante Los Tribunales, 1934; 2; Publication (Reel 8)
      Author: Martinez, Corona
      Notes: y Palacio Zino